<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on CyberChris</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on CyberChris</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Assignments with Org-mode (in Doom Emacs)</title>
      <link>/posts/org-mode-assignments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/org-mode-assignments/</guid>
      <description>Introduction   This post will be a brief tour on writing (work/university) assignments in org-mode, with the goal of producing a nicely typesetted PDF document without having to use much LaTeX.  Everything mentioned will also apply to Emacs in general, but Doom Emacs comes with all the features I mention. Prerequisites   Basic knowledge of org-mode, LaTeX (if math required), and Emacs. (Very) Quick Org-Mode Primer   Org-mode is a plain-text hierarchical markup language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLI Youtube Searcher</title>
      <link>/posts/searchtube-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/searchtube-setup/</guid>
      <description>This was an older writeup of mine that I posted before I had set up this blog. I am reposting it for my blog now.
What&amp;rsquo;s this for? After stumbling upon the youtube-dl program (link to the repo), I was impressed with its functionality but found it quite inconvenient to have to leave the terminal to search for the url. This led me to write this python script that lets you search Youtube and display the video/playlist ID, all in the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day/Night Theme Switching on Doom Emacs (&#43; Bonus Config)</title>
      <link>/posts/doom-emacs-custom/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/doom-emacs-custom/</guid>
      <description>Intro So, inevitably, as one delves deeper into their editor of choice, one finds themselves wishing to customise it to some extent.
Vim can handle this sufficiently, but I found myself reaching the point where my vim config started to get a little bit cluttered. So, after having a look at Emacs, I decided to make the switch, courtesy of Doom Emacs.
The init.el file in the private config already handles most of the configuration you&amp;rsquo;d want to get started with, but there were two things I added to my config.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The (Ultimate) Vim(rc) Guide, with plugins</title>
      <link>/posts/vim-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/vim-guide/</guid>
      <description>Intro So after picking up Vim less than a year ago, and spending a lot of time with it, I can say for sure it is the best text editor I have ever used.
Okay, that&amp;rsquo;s all the Vim propaganda you&amp;rsquo;ll find in this post.
The main aim of this post is to get people new to Vim into a comfortable environment, while also teaching you how to get plugins into your vim config since you&amp;rsquo;ll probably want to customize it, once you get a feel of Vim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning For the Masses (and How to Retrain GPT-2)</title>
      <link>/posts/ml-for-everyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ml-for-everyone/</guid>
      <description>This assumes the reader is on the Windows operating system, but much of the information is relevant to any other OS.
The initial aim of this post was solely a step-by-step guide to retrain GPT-2 using a custom dataset, but I will also ponder on the future of AI and machine learning (not on its progress per se but on how we will interact with it, in the future).
Thanks to Ng Wai Foong for this useful guide on training GPT-2 that helped me a lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RSS Support added</title>
      <link>/posts/rss-added/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/rss-added/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve added support for RSS, allowing you to read posts through your RSS reader of choice. Use the RSS button in the footer of any page to get the link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launching my blog</title>
      <link>/posts/blog-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/blog-launched/</guid>
      <description>Extending my website to include a blog. I&amp;rsquo;ll now be writing articles (occasionaly) here on various tech related topics. Expect more informative/educational types of article rather than journalistic types of article.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>